Danqing Wang

Computer Science - University of California, Santa Barbara - CA ☑ dqwang122@gmail.com • 🖆 dqwang122.github.io

Research Interest: Interested in various generation tasks, including natural language and biological sequence. Devoted to helping the machine generate new content that benefits human life. Mainly focus on (but not limited to):

Natural Language: Generative Agent, Human Alignment, Controllable Generation, etc.

o Biological Sequence: Peptide Design, Antibody Discovery, etc.

Github: https://github.com/dqwang122

Education

PhD in Computer Science UC, Santa Barbara Advisor: Prof. Lei Li 2022.9 - Current

Master in Computer Science

Fudan Univerisity Advisor: Prof. Xipeng Qiu and Prof. Xuanjing Huang 2018.9 - 2021.1

Ranking: Top 5%

Bachelor in Computer Science and Technology

Fudan Univerisity Ranking: Top 10% 2014.9 - 2018.6

Experience

Research Scientist Intern Meta AI (FAIR)

2023.6 - 2023.9 Advisor: Yuandong Tian

Research Scientist ByteDance Research (AI Lab) Advisor: Jiaze Chen, Hao Zhou, and Lei Li 2020.4 - 2022.8

Main Publication

Learning Personalized Story Evaluation %

Danqing Wang, Kevin Yang, Hanlin Zhu, Xiaomeng Yang, Andrew Cohen, Lei Li, Yuandong Tian Preprint on arXiv

- Investigate personalization in open-ended text generation. Propose two personalized story evaluation datasets.
- Develop a personalized story evaluation model PerSE to give detailed review-specific feedback on the story plot. It achieves a higher correlation with humans than GPT-4 by 15.8% on the Kendall correlation.

Learning from Mistakes via Cooperative Study Assistant for Large Language Models %

Danging Wang, Lei Li **EMNLP 2023**

- Propose a general framework SALAM to assist LLM in learning from mistakes through interactive cooperation between the main LLM and the study assistant.
- Develop the model-specific study assistant via the imitation learning of successful experiences, making feedback better aligned with specific LLM behaviors.

Instructscore: Towards Explainable Text Generation Evaluation with Automatic Feedback %

EMNLP 2023 Wenda Xu, Danging Wang, Liangming Pan, Zhenqiao Song, Markus Freitag, William Yang Wang, Lei Li

- Introduce an interpretable metric INSTRUCTSCORE for text generation tasks. It provides comprehensive evaluation by diagnostic reports, culminating in a well-justified final score.
- It significantly surpasses strong baselines in four generation tasks and achieves the best performance in unseen keyword-to-dialogue generation.

ALGO: Synthesizing Algorithmic Programs with Generated Oracle Verifiers %

Kexun Zhang, Danqing Wang, Jingtao Xia, William Yang Wang, Lei Li

NeurIPS 2023

- Introduce a novel framework for algorithm synthesis (ALGO) verified by LLM-generated oracles.
- Equipped with ALGO, we achieve an $8\times$ better one-submission pass rate over the Codex model and a $2.6\times$ better one-submission pass rate over CodeT.

On Pre-training Language Model for Antibody %

Danqing Wang, Fei Ye, Hao Zhou

ICLR 2023

- The first comprehensive antibody benchmark: AnTibody Understanding Evaluation (ATUE).
- Explore the representation capability of pre-trained language models on antibody problems with different specificity, especially the influence of the introduction of evolutionary information (EATLM).

Accelerating Antimicrobial Peptide Discovery with Latent Structure %

Danqing Wang, Zeyu Wen, Fei Ye, Lei Li, Hao Zhou

KDD 2023

- Sample peptides from the latent secondary structure space to control the peptide properties.
- The generated peptides have a high AMP probability (93.62%) and 2/21 show high activity in wet laboratory experiments.

Contrastive Aligned Joint Learning for Multilingual Summarization %

Danqing Wang, Jiaze Chen, Hao Zhou, Xipeng Qiu, Lei Li

ACL 2021 Finding

- A large-scale multilingual summarization corpus MLGSum with 1.1 million articles and summaries in 12 languages.
- Propose two tasks, contrastive sentence ranking and sentence-aligned substitution, for multilingual summarization.

Heterogeneous Graph Neural Networks for Extractive Document Summarization %

Danqing Wang*, Pengfei Liu*, Yining Zheng, Xipeng Qiu and Xuanjing Huang

ACL 2020

- Introduce word nodes to model the cross-sentence relationship for extractive summarization.
- Easily adapt the graph model from single to multiple document summarization.

Extractive Summarization as Text Matching &

Ming Zhong*, Pengfei Liu*, Yiran Chen, Danqing Wang, Xipeng Qiu and Xuanjing Huang

ACL 2020

- Formulate extractive summarization as a semantic text matching problem and select sentences in the summary level.
- Achieve superior performance on six benchmark datasets, including state-of-the-art extractive results on CNN/DailyMail.

Searching for Effective Neural Extractive Summarization: What Works and What's Next %

Ming Zhong*, Pengfei Liu*, **Danqing Wang**, Xipeng Qiu, Xuanjing Huang

ACL 2019

- Models with an autoregressive decoder are prone to achieving better performance against non-auto-regressive ones.
- LSTM is more likely to suffer from the architecture overfitting problem while Transformer is more robust.

Academic Services

- Program Committee of ACL, EMNLP, AAAI, ICML, ICLR
- TA for CS190I Deep Learning (Winter 2023) and CS165B Machine Learning (Spring 2023)
- Local Organization Chair of Socal NLP Symposium 2022

Honor

- Sept 2022 Academic Excellence Fellowship
- May 2021 Shanghai Outstanding Graduates (5% of graduates)
- **Nov. 2020** Venustech Scholarship (1% of Fudan students)
- **Sept. 2019** Scholarship for Outstanding Students (First Prize)
- Dec. 2017 Fudan's Undergraduate Research Opportunities Program